<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic xml:lang="en-US" id="_10.24_Page_Program_PP_"><title>Page Program (PP)</title><body><p>The Page Program (PP) instruction is for programming the memory to be "0". A Write Enable (WREN) instruction must execute to set the Write Enable Latch (WEL) bit before sending the Page Program (PP). The device programs only the last 256 data bytes sent to the device. If the entire 256 data bytes are going to be programmed, A7-A0 (The eight least significant address bits) should be set to 0. If the eight least significant address bits (A7-A0) are not all 0, all transmitted data going beyond the end of the current page are programmed from the start address of the same page (from the address A7-A0 are all 0). If more than 256 bytes are sent to the device, the data of the last 256-byte is programmed at the request page and previous data will be disregarded.	If less than 256 bytes are sent to the device, the data is programmed at the requested address of the page.</p><p>For the very best performance, programming should be done in full pages of 256 bytes aligned on 256 byte boundaries with each Page being programmed only once. Using the Page Program (PP) command to load an entire page, within the page boundary, will save overall programming time versus loading less than a page into the program buffer.</p><p>It is possible to program from one byte up to a page size in each Page programming operation. Please refer to the P25Q serial flash application note for multiple byte program operation within one page.</p><p>The sequence of issuing PP instruction is: CS# goes low→ sending PP instruction code→ 3-byte address on SI→ at least 1-byte on data on SI→ CS# goes high.</p><p>The CS# must be kept low during the whole Page Program cycle; The CS# must go high exactly at the byte boundary (the latest eighth bit of data being latched in), otherwise the instruction will be rejected and will not be</p><p>2072</p><p>2073</p><p>2074</p><p>2075</p><p>2076</p><p>2077</p><p>2078</p><p>2079</p><p>executed.</p><p>The self-timed Page Program Cycle time (tPP) is initiated as soon as Chip Select (CS#) goes high. The Write in Progress (WIP) bit still can be checked during the Page Program cycle is in progress. The WIP sets 1 during the tPP timing, and sets 0 when Page Program Cycle is completed, and the Write Enable Latch (WEL) bit is reset. If the page is protected by BP4, BP3, BP2, BP1, BP0 bits, the Page Program (PP) instruction will not be executed.	The SIO[3:1] are "don't care".</p><p><image href="../images/image119.png" height="136" width="143" alt="???"/><b>Figure 10-24 Page Program (PP) Sequence (Command 02)</b></p><p>1048</p><p>1049</p><p>1050</p><p>1051</p><p>1052</p><p>1053</p><p>1054</p><p>1055</p></body></topic>