<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic xml:lang="en-US" id="_10.7_Active_Status_Interrupt_ASI_"><title>Active Status Interrupt (ASI)</title><body><p>To simplify the readout of the WIP bit, the Active Status Interrupt command (25h) may be used. It is then not necessary to continuously read the status register, it is sufficient to monitor the value of the SO line. If the SO line is connected to an interrupt line on the host controller, the host controller may be in sleep mode until the SO line indicates that the device is ready for the next command.</p><p>The WIP bit can be read at any time, including during an internally self-timed program or erase operation.</p><p>To enable the Active Status Interrupt command, the CS pin must first be asserted and the opcode of 25h must be clocked into the device. For SPI Mode3, at least one dummy bit has to be clocked into the device after the last bit of the opcode has been clocked in. (In most cases, this is most easily done by sending a dummy byte to the device.) The value of the SI line after the opcode is clocked in is of no significance to the operation. For SPI Mode 0, this dummy bit (dummy byte) is not required.</p><p>The value of WIP is then output on the SO line, and is continuously updated by the device for as long as the CS pin remains asserted. Additional clocks on the SCK pin are not required. If the WIP bit changes from 1 to 0 while the CS pin is asserted, the SO line will change from 1 to 0. (The WIP bit cannot change from 0 to 1 during an operation, so if the SO line already is 0, it will not change.)</p><p>Deasserting the CS pin will terminate the Active Status Interrupt operation and put the SO pin into a</p><p>high-impedance state. The CS pin can be deasserted at any time and does not require that a full byte of data be read.</p><p>The sequence of issuing ASI instruction is: CS# goes low→ sending ASI instruction code→ WIP data out on SO</p><p><image href="../images/image56.png" height="135" width="143" alt="???"/><b>Figure 10-7 Active Status Interrupt (ASI) Sequence (Command 25)</b></p></body></topic>