<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic xml:lang="en-US" id="_10.8_Write_Status_Register_WRSR_"><title>Write Status Register (WRSR)</title><body><p>The Write Status Register (WRSR) command allows new values to be written to the Status Register. Before it can be accepted, a Write Enable (WREN) command must previously have been executed. After the Write Enable (WREN) command has been decoded and executed, the device sets the Write Enable Latch (WEL).</p><p>The Write Status Register (WRSR) command has no effect on S15, S10, S1 and S0 of the Status Register. CS# must be driven high after the eighth or sixteen bit of the data byte has been latched in. If not, the Write Status Register (WRSR) command is not executed. If CS# is driven high after eighth bit of the data byte, the CMP and QE and SRP1 bits will be cleared to 0. As soon as CS# is driven high, the self-timed Write Status Register cycle (whose duration is tW) is initiated. While the Write Status Register cycle is in progress, the Status Register may still be read to check the value of the Write In Progress (WIP) bit. The Write In Progress (WIP) bit is 1 during the self-timed Write Status Register cycle, and is 0 when it is completed. When the cycle is completed, the Write Enable Latch (WEL) is reset.</p><p>The Write Status Register (WRSR) command allows the user to change the values of the Block Protect (BP4, BP3, BP2, BP1, and BP0) bits, to define the size of the area that is to be treated as read-only, as defined in Table1. The Write Status Register (WRSR) command also allows the user to set or reset the Status Register Protect (SRP1 and SRP0) bits in accordance with the Write Protect (WP#) signal. The Status Register Protect (SRP1 and SRP0) bits and Write Protect (WP#) signal allow the device to be put in the Hardware Protected Mode. The Write Status Register (WRSR) command is not executed once the Hardware Protected Mode is entered.</p><p>The sequence of issuing WRSR instruction is: CS# goes low→ sending WRSR instruction code→ Status Register data on SI→CS# goes high.</p><p>The CS# must go high exactly at the 8 bits or 16 bits data boundary; otherwise, the instruction will be rejected and not executed. The self-timed Write Status Register cycle time (tW) is initiated as soon as Chip Select (CS#) goes high. The Write in Progress (WIP) bit still can be checked during the Write Status Register cycle is in progress. The WIP sets 1 during the tW timing, and sets 0 when Write Status Register Cycle is completed, and the Write Enable Latch (WEL) bit is reset.</p><p><image href="../images/image63.png" height="134" width="143" alt="???"/><b>Figure 10-8 Write Status Register (WRSR) Sequence (Command 01)</b></p></body></topic>