<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic xml:lang="en-US" id="_10.31_Release_form_Deep_Power-Down_RDP_"><title>Release form Deep Power-Down (RDP), Read Electronic Signature (RES)</title><body><p>The Release from Deep Power-down (RDP) instruction is terminated by driving Chip Select (CS#) High. When Chip Select (CS#) is driven high, the device is put in the Stand-by Power mode. If the device was not previously in the Deep Power-down mode, the transition to the Stand-by Power mode is immediate. If the device was previously in the Deep Power-down mode, though, the transition to the Stand-by Power mode is delayed by tRES2, and Chip Select (CS#) must remain High for at least tRES2(max). Once in the Stand-by Power mode, the device waits to be selected, so that it can receive, decode and execute instructions.</p><p>RES instruction is for reading out the old style of 8-bit Electronic Signature, whose values are shown as table of ID Definitions. This is not the same as RDID instruction. It is not recommended to use for new design. For new design, please use RDID instruction.	Even in Deep power-down mode, the RDP and RES are also allowed to be executed, only except the device is in progress of program/erase/write cycle; there's no effect on the current program/erase/ write cycle in progress.</p><p>The RES instruction is ended by CS# goes high after the ID been read out at least once. The ID outputs repeatedly if continuously send the additional clock cycles on SCLK while CS# is at low.	If the device was not previously in Deep Power-down mode, the device transition to standby mode is immediate.	If the device was previously in Deep Power-down mode, there's a delay of tRES2 to transit to standby mode, and CS# must remain to high at least tRES2 (max).	Once in the standby mode, the device waits to be selected, so it can be receive, decode, and execute instruction.</p><p>The RDP instruction is for releasing from Deep Power-Down Mode.</p><p>CS#</p><p><image href="../images/image177.png" height="134" width="278" alt="???"/><image href="../images/image184.png" height="134" width="493" alt="???"/><b>Figure 10-31 Read Electronic Signature (RES) Sequence (Command AB)</b></p><p><b>Figure 10-32 Release from Deep Power-down (RDP) Sequence (Command AB)</b></p><p><image href="../images/image187.png" height="136" width="145" alt="???"/></p></body></topic>