<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic xml:lang="en-US" id="_10.16_4_X_IO_Read_Mode_4READ_"><title>4 X IO Read Mode (4READ)</title><body><p>The 4READ instruction enable quad throughput of Serial NOR Flash in read mode. A Quad Enable (QE) bit of status Register must be set to "1" before sending the 4READ instruction. The address is latched on rising edge of SCLK, and data of every four bits (interleave on 4 I/O pins) shift out on the falling edge of SCLK at a maximum frequency fQ. The first address byte can be at any location. The address is automatically increased to the next higher address after each byte data is shifted out, so the whole memory can be read out at a single 4READ instruction. The address counter rolls over to 0 when the highest address has been reached. Once writing 4READ instruction, the following address/dummy/data out will perform as 4-bit instead of previous 1-bit.</p><p>The sequence of issuing 4READ instruction is: CS# goes low→ sending 4READ instruction→ 24-bit address interleave on SIO3, SIO2, SIO1 &amp; SIO0→2+4 dummy cycles→data out interleave on SIO3, SIO2, SIO1 &amp; SIO0</p><p>- to end 4READ operation can use CS# to high at any time during data out.</p><p>Another sequence of issuing 4READ instruction especially useful in random access is: CS# goes low→sending 4READ instruction→3-bytes address interleave on SIO3, SIO2, SIO1 &amp; SIO0  → “Continuous Read Mode” byte M[7:0]→ 4 dummy cycles  →data out still CS# goes high  → CS# goes low (reduce 4 Read instruction)</p><p>→24-bit random access address.</p><p>In the performance-enhancing mode, the “Continuous Read Mode” bits M[5:4] = (1,0) can make this mode continue and reduce the next 4READ instruction. Once M[5:4 ] ≠ (1,0) and afterwards CS# is raised and then lowered, the system then will escape from performance enhance mode and return to normal operation. A “Continuous Read Mode” Reset command can be used to reset (M5-4) before issuing normal command While Program/Erase/Write Status Register cycle is in progress, 4READ instruction is rejected without any impact on the Program/Erase/Write Status Register current cycle.</p><p><image href="../images/image107.png" height="135" width="145" alt="???"/><b>Figure 10-16 4 X IO Read Mode Sequence (Command EB M5-4 ≠ (1,0))</b></p></body></topic>